# **RÉSUMÉ**

## John Krug

DoB: 12/01/1963

email: jh.krug@gmail.com	Address: Calle Adrián López Iriarte 27, Padul, Granada, 18640, Andalusia, España
Tel: +34 644 334 591. Message first using email, Signal, or WhatsApp.	LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jhkrug GitHub: https://www.github.com/jhkrug

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I'm an experienced information technology professional. I have worked in development, systems management, support, data management, and technical documentation, often in leadership roles. I have worked in the public, private, and higher education sectors.

Most recently, I have been enjoying technical writing using a docs-as-code approach as part of documentation teams at OutSystems and SUSE.

#### **SKILLS**

I have worked independently and in teams, in large and small organizations. Recently, this has all been remote work with geographically dispersed teams. I have been an employee, a director/owner, and technical manager.

I'm currently working in agile documentation development teams using Git, GitHub, Markdown, Slack, and Google Suite or Microsoft tools. The work is documenting cloud products and developer tools.

At Lancaster I worked at system management, data wrangling, Oracle, SQL, ETL processes, and data visualization. These skills were applied to library management and analytics processes. I did frequent training sessions for library staff.

I have used and integrated many information technologies, databases, networks, and tools over the years. I am a user of Linux and familiar with Windows and MacOS. I have coded in many languages over the years (Shell, Assembly, C, OCCAM, SQL, Lua, Python, Shell, etc.). I have written much technical material and documentation regarding systems integration, automation, and data management. I have learned new technologies, many times, implementing and integrating them.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Technical Writer, SUSE, July 2023 - Present

I'm part of the SUSE Rancher cloud engineering division. I write documentation for open-source cloud products, working daily with engineers and project managers. I'm involved with the Epinio, Kubewarden and Longhorn projects. Documentation tools are Google Workspace, GitHub, git, vsCode, Docusaurus, and markdown. It's a fully remote role using a range of collaboration tools.

### Senior Technical Writer, OutSystems, July 2022 - May 2023

I worked on product documentation for the OutSystems product suite. I was an agile team lead, also updating and writing documentation. There was daily collaboration with engineers and product owners. We used Zoom, JIRA, Confluence, Figma, Google Workspace, markdown, git, VScode, and GitHub. I enjoyed being back in full-time work in a highly technical, client-focused organization. This was a fully remote role.

### Library Consultant, Independent, May 2017 - July 2022

For the University of Leeds I developed a set of Alma and Primo analytics training materials for library staff. The CC-licensed training materials website is archived at Netlify. The training materials are in asciidoc and Antora with accompanying video material. The source is on GitLab. This was a fully remote role.

In April 2018, I organized and presented at a training workshop on Alma Analytics for UK Ex Libris users in London on behalf of the British user group.

### Systems and Analytics Manager, Lancaster University Library, April 2002 - March 2017

I had 15 years at Lancaster University Library, starting as the Library Systems Coordinator. The first role was the implementation of the Aleph library management system from Ex Libris. Other Ex Libris systems were implemented; Metalib and SFX (2004), Primo (2010), and the new cloud-based library management system, Alma (2013).

For IGeLU[1] and ELUNA[2], I established the first Analytics working group[3] to promote the use of Alma Analytics in libraries and work through issues with Ex Libris. This involved coordinating 14 library professionals around the world and building the wider Ex Libris Analytics community at conferences and workshops.

I gained an ILM Level 5 qualification in leadership and management. I received a Lancaster University staff award for outstanding achievement.

#### Before 2002

- With colleagues, I started an IT consultancy, Xinetica Ltd (1996-2002). We did well for a few years before the first internet crash. I worked at ASDA and the Financial Services Authority.
- I was a consultant at Protek (1994-1996) working mostly at North West Water.
- I was a systems administrator at Barclays de Zoet Wedd (1992-1993) in London. I worked on the FX derivatives desk. A high pressure environment.
- During 1991, after my M.Sc. I worked at the NTSC[4] with parallel processing industrial research and the INMOS transputer.
- I was a Lance Corporal in the British Army, Royal Artillery (1983-86). I can drive a tracked armored personnel carrier if necessary. :-)

#### **EDUCATION**

- 1990-1991 University of Sheffield, M.Sc. Software Systems Technology
- 1985-1989 Open University (UK), undergraduate courses at in mathematics and computing.

#### **REFERENCES**

From Masud Khokhar.	From David Summers	

#### **PORTFOLIO**

• GitHub: https://www.github.com/jhkrug

• GitLab: https://gitlab.com/libtics

• Libtics: https://libtics.netlify.app

• A very occasional blog: https://jhkrug.github.io.

#### **FOOTNOTES**

- 1 International Group of Ex Libris Users
- 2 Ex Libris Users of North America
- 3 Analytics SIWG (Special Interest Working Group)
- 4 National Transputer Support Centre in Sheffield. UK government funded to promote parallel processing using the INMOS Transputer. The Transputer was a microprocessor with facilities enabling massive parallelism when connected with other transputers.